A Guide to the G. Truman Ward Collection, 1958-2005
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
This series remains unprocessed and is currently restricted to researchers. Included is a preliminary inventory of the oversize drawings and blueprints preserved by G.T. Ward. These drawings were originally in an oversize storage cabinet that Ward had brought home from the Ward/Hall office and placed in his garage and used for other purposes. The forgotten drawings were originally rolled up and only discovered after cleaning out the cabinet. It is unknown if a more complete architectural archives of Ward/Hall still exists elsewhere.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Photographs from this collection are digitally available on the online Fairfax County Public Library Photographic Archive.
None
Index Terms
Architecture - Virginia; Architecture - Virginia - Fairfax County; Center for Innovative Technology (Virginia); Vosbeck-Ward & Associates; Ward & Hall; Ward & Hall & Associates; Ward, George Truman (1927-2020); Ward/Hall Associates
Container List
- Series 1: Professional, 1961-2005
  - Framed certificate, National Council of Architectural Registration Board, Architect License No. 4077, 1961 August 1 (Box 2)
  - Portfolio, Ward-Hale Design Associates, Inc., c. 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Virginia Record" magazine (Virginia Power - Northern Division Headquarters), 1986 May-June (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Outline Biography of George Truman Ward" by G.T. Ward, 2005 June 22 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Christmas card, "Season's Greetings from Ward/Hall Associates AIA" (features Riverside Baptist Church), Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Undated (Drawer OV Drawer, Folder Poster, "Season's Greetings, Ward/Hall")
- Series 2: Photo Albums, 1961-1984
  - Photo Album #1, 1964-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photo Album #2, 1961-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photo Album #3, 1964-1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photo Album #4, 1968-1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook on Lake Montclair Development, Dumfries, VA, 1968 (Box 2)
- Series 3: Center for Innovative Technology, 1986-1990
  - Commemorative plaque, CIT Building Groundbreaking, 1986 September 11 (Box 2)
  - Commemorative clock, CIT Building Groundbreaking, 1986 September 11 (Box 4)
  - Framed "Progressive Architecture" CIT Building article, 1989 August (Box 2)
  - "Progressive Architecture" magazine (CIT Building), 1989 August (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Commemorative model, CIT Building Dedication, 1989 September 20 (Box 4)
  - Dedication program, Center for Innovative Technology, 1989 September 20 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Inform" magazine (CIT Building), 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Promotional booklet, "Virginia's Center for Innovative Technology", c. 1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Framed photo, CIT Building under construction, Undated (Box 3)
  - Mounted photo, Aerial of CIT Building under construction, Undated (Box 3)
  - Mounted photo, CIT Building under construction, Undated (Box 3)
  - Mounted photo, CIT Building under construction, Undated (Box 3)
  - Mounted photo, CIT Building model, Undated (Box 3)
- Series 4: Architectural Drawings and Blueprints (UNPROCESSED and RESTRICTED), 1958-2002
  - Project No. 728: Addition to Annandale Baptist Church (Vosbeck & Ward), 1958 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 7211: Enlisted Men's Club, Norfolk Naval Shipyard, Portsmouth, Virginia, 1973 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 7346: Dulles Town Center, 1973-1974 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - FY-1977 Family Housing 152 Units, U.S. Naval Air Station, Keflavik, Iceland, 1977 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 7609: Unidentified Church, 1976 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 7832 C: Essex Village, Laburnum Avenue, Henrico County, Virginia, 1980 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 7959: Zoning Study Lynch/Colvert/Goode Parcel, Fairfax County, Virginia, Undated (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 8136: Franklin Farms Elementary School (Oak Hill Elementary), 1981 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 8136 and 8137: Newington Forest and Franklin Elementary Schools, 1982 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 8137: Newington Forest Elementary School, 1981 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 8157: First Assembly of God Church, Springfield, Va., 1981 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 85032: Dulles Town Center, 1987-1988 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 85033: Rocks Parcel Number Two Building One, 1987 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 85035: Rocks-Dulles Parcel 4 or Rockspoint At Dulles Parcel 4, 1985 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 85036: Center for Innovative Technology, Fairfax/Loudoun Counties, Virginia, 1987 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 86012: Burn Brae Dinner Theater, 1988 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 86082: West Springfield High School Renovation, 1988 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 88020: Washingtonian Center, 1988-1989 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 88020.002: Washingtonian Center Parking Garage (& Cinema), 1988 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 88020-09: Washingtonian Center Retail, 1988 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 88063: Cineplex Odeon Cinemas Fairfax Square, 1989 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 88083 and 88109: Cineplex Odeon Washingtonian, 1989 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 90057: Aldrin Elementary School, 1991, 1994 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 90085: Alterations and Additions to Lynnbrook Elementary School, 1992, 1994 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 91089: Cineplex Odeon Washingtonian, 1994-1995 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 92057: Educational Building Addition to Spotsylvania Presbyterian Church, Fredericksburg, Virginia, 1996 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 95020: Virginia Tech Athletic Facility, Blacksburg, Virginia, 1996 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. WC3460: Madison Forest Executive Office & Industrial Park - Phase I, 1991-1998 (Drawer OV Drawer)
  - Project No. 005: Gymnasium/Classroom Building, Word of Life Assembly of God Church, Backlick and Edsall Roads, Fairfax County, Virginia, 2002 (Drawer OV Drawer)